本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 小坏玩意儿 老虎娘 红鼻子的UFO skywalker 小白兔  Saturnine  粟
校对/后期： 苏三
阿加莎・克里斯汀: 马普尔小姐探案集\N第四季第4集
着火了
Fire!
鲁思
Ruth!
鲁思 发生了什么...
Oh, Ruth, what on earth ...
刘易斯 我的东西
Oh, Lewis! All my things!
- 刘易斯 - 女士们
- Lewis! - Ladies.
《借镜杀人》
您的茶 夫人
Your tea, madam.
他们理所当然地将火灾归咎于线路故障
Natural, they all put the fire down to a faulty wire,
但我清楚自己看到了什么
but I know what I saw.
有个男人 我现在还能想起他
There was a man. I can see him now.
他...他悄悄穿过走廊
He was...was stilling across the hallway.
他长什么样 鲁思
How would you describe him, Ruth?
- 邪恶 邪恶至极 - 我知道了
- Wicked. Quite, quite wicked. - I see.
当然 卡莉・路易斯说我是在做梦
Of course, Carrie Louise says that I dreamed it all,
但我姐姐从来都不愿意听不愉快的真相
but my sister never had any time for unpalatable truths.
简 你认为有人能猜出
Do you think anyone could possibly guess, Jane,
你我几乎同龄吗
that you and I are practically the same age?
肯定不会
Not for a moment, I'm sure.
我嘛 每分钟都在衰老
I'm afraid, you see, I look every minute of my age.
才不会
No!
这起火灾是何时发生的
When was it, this fire?
六周前
Six weeks ago.
我刚从纽约飞来与受托人见面
I'd just flown in from New York for a meeting of the Trustees.
卡莉・路易斯的丈夫肯定看见了什么
Surely Carrie Louise's husband must have seen something?
刘易斯满眼都是他亲爱的妻子和她的事业
Lewis only has eyes for his dear wife and her blessed cause.
她还在追求自己的事业吗
She's still keeping up with her causes?
太阳可不会打西边出来
Does the sun rise in the morning?
一般来说 一个年轻姑娘做这件事很时尚
Naturally, such thing is fashionable when one's a young girl.
我记得你当时想做一名修女
You were off to be a nun, I believe.
是 很有可能 但婚姻拴住了我
Yes. Very possibly. But marriage knocks sense into one,
天知道自从卡莉・路易斯结婚后
and God knows Carrie Louise has had plenty of practice
她付出了多少努力
ever since she threw herself at that luringly glump.
她第一任丈夫 古尔布兰德森先生
Her first husband, Mr. Gulbrandsen,
是个慈善家吧
He was something of a philanthropyst, wasn't he?
又结了两次婚 她还在靠他的遗产生活
And two husbands later, she is still living of his inheritance.
现在她又瞄上了新目标
And she's supered herself with this latest cause.
罪犯们
Criminals.
她以为自己能和他们"做点什么"
She imagines she can "do something" with them.
所以 他们来了 在她花园尽头
So, there they are, all living it up in a so-called
所谓的"改造工厂"里工作生活
"Reform Facility" at the bottom of her garden.
- 你担心的就是这个吗 - 我不知道
- And this is what you afraid of? - I don't know.
每次我和她在一起 我感觉总有个人在她周围
All the time I was with her, I felt this-this presence around her.
然后...她书房的大火
And then... that fire in her study.
那座房子里的某个人想要伤害我姐姐
Someone in that house wishes my sister harm.
- 我敢说这一切听上去很偏激 - 不
- And I dare say this all sounds quite mad to you. - Oh, no.
- 你相信我吗 - 我相信你的判断
- You believe me? - I trust your conviction.
没有什么事能让你惊奇 对吧 简
Nothing has ever surprised you, has it, Jane?
因为你总是做最坏的打算
Because you always think the worst.
最坏的结果通常会发生
The worst is so often true.
那你会尽快去吧
Then you'll go? As soon as you can?
你记不记得她和古尔布兰德森
Do you remember how she and Gulbrandsen
多么想要一个自己的孩子
longed for a child of their own?
他们不是最终收养了一个吗
Didn't they adopt in the end?
我见过那孩子 非常漂亮的女孩
I think I met the child. A very pretty girl.
是的 吉娜 一个迷人的小可爱
Yes. Gina. A bewitching little thing.
然后 如你所料 没过多久
Then, as so often happens, not long after,
卡莉・路易斯发现自己怀孕了
Carrie Louise found herself pregnant.
通常 人们不会善待养子
Normally, it's hard lines on the adopted child,
但他们不同
but not in their case.
卡莉・路易斯生怕自己偏心
Carrie Louise was so anxious not to make the difference between them two
所以米尔德里德出世之后
that when Mildred came along,
任何事她都偏心小吉娜
if anything, she tended to over-indulge the little Gina,
把她的亲生孩子晾在一边
while her natural child was left to fan herself.
可怜的米尔德里德 从未得到过母亲的爱
Poor Mildred. She never stood a chance.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Oh! Hello.
这旅行袋真漂亮
Oh, what a nice trim bag.
您一定是...
You must be ...
一号站台下一班列车
The next train on platform one
四点五十从帕丁顿开出
is the 4:50 from Paddington.
明天到达小佩维雷尔
All stations to Little Peverell tomorrow.
您一定是简姑妈
I said you must be Aunt Jane.
- 你一定是吉娜 - 您怎么知道
- And you must be Gina. - How did you guess?
不说也知道 走吧
Don't answer that. Come on.
入此地者将重获希望
这一定是那个著名的工厂
This must be the famous facility.
真是不可救药
Incorrigible.
- 你说谁 亲爱的 - 当然是他们
- Who, dear? - Well, them, of course.
妈妈
Mommy!
简
Jane!
我亲爱的卡莉・路易斯 你好吗
My dear Carrie Louise. How are you?
身体老了 但还是一如既往的固执
The flesh is weak, but the spirit's as stubborn as ever.
你喝茶吗
Would you take tea?
我一直站着喝
I always take mine standing up,
不然就再也站不起来了 你说呢
or otherwise one would seat around forever, don't you think?
请允许我介绍刘易斯
Allow me to introduce Lewis ...
我亲爱的丈夫和部落的酋长
treasured husband and chief of my tribe.
- 嗨 - 你好啊
- Ow. - How do you do?
业余爱好 为爱献身
Amateur dramatics. The things we do for love.
我觉得你看起来很勇猛
I think you look quite fierce.
- 你说呢 亲爱的 - 我不喜欢这种事
- Don't you, dear? - I have no head for such matters.
我女儿 米尔德里德
My daughter. Mildred.
真高兴终于见到你了
How very nice to meet you after this long while.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
我打算将马普尔小姐安置在法比安套房 夫人
I've put Miss Marple in the Fabian Suite, ma'm.
好主意
Good thinking.
简 这是朱丽叶・贝耶维 简直是我的一切
Jane, this is Juliet Bellever, who's simply everything to me,
护士 保镖 管家 也是忠实的朋友
nurse, dragon, watch-dog... and very faithful friend.
乔莉 晚饭吃什么 我饿死了
Jolly! What's for dinner? I'm starved.
凯洛格先生认为 食物中额外的蛋白质
As Mr. Kellogg approval, an excess of protein in the diet
会激发罪犯的犯罪意识
excites all the wrong instincts amongst with criminal intents
我们发现大麦是绝佳的替代品
We found in barley an excelent substitute.
- 是这样吧 马弗里克医生 - 确实
- Isn't that so, Dr. Maverick? - Indeed.
我希望我们每周聚餐一次
I like us all to eat together once a week.
想让所有犯人感觉我们是一家人
I like all my charges to feel like they're part of the family.
我们确实是 亲爱的
And so we do, my dear.
他们真般配
They make a splendid couple.
我希望不是
I should hope not!
那是我继子 斯蒂文・雷斯塔瑞克
That's my stepson, Stephen Restarick.
我第二任丈夫约翰尼的孩子
By my second husband, Johnny.
- 那个戏剧制作人 - 当然
- The theater producer. - Of course he is.
在这里万事皆可
All matter of waflles and strays under this roof.
每个人都会犯错
Eveyone's allowed an error of judgement.
爸爸是你的 是吧 亲爱的
Dad was yours. Isn't that right, darling?
有什么好笑的
Not quite a laughing matter.
我妻子在戏剧评论中说斯蒂文是不可或缺的
Steven has made himself indispensible to my wife's dramatic review
卡莉・路易斯让我每年出演她的一部戏
Carrie Louise chooses me to stage a show for her every year.
为了鼓舞军队士气
Moral booster for the troops.
你继承父亲的戏剧事业了吗 雷斯塔瑞克先生
Are you in the theater like your father, Mr. Restarick?
我从事纺织业
I'm in fabrics,
软装饰
soft furnishing.
让我不再淘气
Keeps me out of mischief.
但斯蒂维会在春天红透西区
But Stevie is going to storm the West End, in the spring,
是吧 亲爱的
aren't you, darling?
吉娜的丈夫呢
And Gina's husband?
一位叫瓦利・哈德的绅士 来自怀俄明
A gentleman called Wally Hudd. From Wyoming.
哈德先生非常喜欢烤鸡
Mr. Hudd has a great fondness for grilled chicken.
他和吉娜在诺曼底登陆那天相遇
He and Gina met during D-Day.
你可以想象那个画面
You can imagine.
正相反 我觉得他们非常般配
On the contrary, I think they're admirably suited.
有什么好的战争故事 瓦利
Did you have a good war, Wally?
我没死
Well, it didn't kill me.
但也没变得更坚强
But it didn't make me stronger.
我能帮您吗
May I help you?
不 不
No! No,
那场火灾真令人遗憾
such a pity, uh? The fire.
没错
Quite.
几个月之后才恢复元气
Set us back some months.
- 我是艾德加・罗森 - 我叫简・马普尔
- Edgar Lawson. - Jane Marple.
我想也是
So I gather.
你...为卡莉・路易斯工作吗
Uh... You work for Carrie Louise?
为塞罗科尔德先生
For Mr Serrocold.
我是他的私人秘书
I'm his personal secretary.
- 听上去很重要 - 有时是
- Sounds terribly important. - Has its moments.
但...
But...
- 我能说个秘密吗 - 当然
- May I speak in confidence? - Of course.
您要发誓
Swear it, please.
我不想动摇他的地位
You see, I have no wish to compromise his position.
- 塞罗科尔德先生的吗 - 不
- Mr. Serrocold's? - No.
我父亲的
My father.
其实我是
You see, I am, in fact,
温斯顿・丘吉尔的儿子
Winston Churchill's son.
是 看得出来
Yes, I think I do see.
他尽其所能帮助我 但他们监视我
He does what he can, but they spy on me.
总是这样
Always have done.
还有...政治诽谤运动
And... the whispering campaign.
如果不是这该死的政治诽谤
If it wasn't for that damned whispering, you see?
有谁看见塞罗科尔德夫人了
Has anyone's seen Mrs. Serrocold?
我也奇怪呢
I was thinking the same thing.
这是她这周第二次忘记吃药了
It's the second time this week she forgot her tonic.
这个女人根本不在乎自己的健康
The woman has no head for her own safety.
塞罗科尔德夫人 米尔德里德小姐
Mrs. Serrocold? Miss Mildred?
妈妈
Mommy?
- 她们在干什么 - 天哪 妈妈
- What is that? - Oh, gosh! Mommy!
妈妈
Mommy!
吉娜
Gina!
快回来 你会够不着底的
Come back this minute! You'll be out of your depth!
亲爱的 求求你
Honey, please!
你们也下来吧
Aren't you going to come in?
轻轻一跃 清醒一下
A quick leap. Wonderfully refreshing.
- 吉娜 - 闭上眼睛
- Gina! - Advert your eyes.
- 你也是 老兄 - 别这么叫我
- You too, bro. - Don't call me that!
你在想什么
What were you thinking of?
斯蒂文碰巧提到
It happens that Stephen mentioned that
潜水能治疗关节炎
a cool dive does wonders for arthritis.
你知道妈妈 总是第一个挑战自己
And you know mommy, always the first to the barricade.
- 但她几乎不会游泳 - 瞎说
- But she can hardly swim! - Oh, nonsense.
救命 救命
Help! Help!
现在高兴了 今天的混乱还不够多吗
Happy now? Caused sufficient chaos for one night?
别说了 蜜儿
Give me a rest, Mil.
我来了 我来了
I'm coming! I'm coming!
小心 刘易斯 水很深
Careful, Lewis, it does get deep there.
我来了 坚持住
I'm coming! Hang on!
你怎么想 马普尔小姐 脑子犯抽了吧
What do they say, Miss Marple? Blood ran out?
塞罗科尔德先生会游泳吗
Is he an able swimmer, Mr Serrocold?
这儿就没个人真的会游泳吗
Can anyone here actually swim?
受不了了 你们就会光说不练
Very good, low lovers,
我一个人去救他们 就算死了也算试过了
I'll rescue them myself or die trying.
你开玩笑吧
You won't do that.
吉娜 你不许下去
Gina, don't you dare!
米尔德里德  那些小伙子是什么人
I say, Mildred, who are those young men?
看来你的祈祷管用了 蜜儿
Looks like your prayers were answered, Mil.
亲爱的鲁思 我希望能够对你说
My dear Ruth, i had hoped to
你担心卡莉・路易斯的人身安全
dispel your concerns
完全是杞人忧天
over Carrie Louise's safety,
但是恐怕事与愿违
but I fear I can not.
她还是像以前那样开朗阳光
She has the same bright spirit as ever,
但正如你先前所暗示的那样
but there may, as you suggested,
斯托尼盖特可能真的暗潮涌动
be dark forces at play here in Stonygates.
吉娜正如你描述的那样迷人
Gina is as bewitching as you say.
家中的继子
Certainly, the stepson,
斯蒂文・雷斯塔瑞克也发现了这一点
Stephen Restarick, finds her so,
但她的丈夫却对这一切视若无睹 漠不关心
while her american husband looks away, as if indifferent.
还有艾德加・罗森
And then there is Edgar Lawson.
他与周围格格不入
He is maladjusted, certainly.
除此之外 艾德加・罗森还有一点不对劲
But there is something else a little wrong about Edgar Lawson.
但这跟卡莉・路易斯有什么关系
There what is, and it is and when it touches Carrie Louise,
我还说不好
I can not yet say.
那件事一定吓到你了
It must have been a terrible shock for you.
我是指 那场火灾
The fire, I mean.
我书房的那次吗
In my study?
没那回事 只是场意外
Oh, no, no. That was an accident.
只是
It's just ...
这件事千万不要
Promise you won't breathe a word
让可怜的刘易斯知道 但是...
of this to my poor Lewis, but ...
我的英雄
Oh, the hero of the hour!
阿尔巴特・安东尼
Albator, Anthony!
夫人
Madam.
八次盗窃 四次入侵民宅
Eight cons for burglary, four for breaking and entering,
还有更多我数都数不过来的罪行
and more gravous harm than I have fingers and toes to count,
但是昨天晚上 这位绅士救了我的命
but last night, this gentleman saved my life.
虽然场面挺狼狈的
All it takes is a little dignity,
还得跟内政局解释才行
though try and say that to the Home Office.
这位是惠特斯特布尔・欧尼斯特
And this is Whitstable Ernest.
你的西红柿长势好吗
How are your tomatoes prospering?
都熟透了 夫人
Ripe as prune, ma'am.
想尝一个吗 夫人
Care to try one, madam?
好的 谢谢
Very nice. Thank you.
塞罗科尔德先生现在恢复了吧
Mr. Serrocold's fully recovered from his paddle, I hope?
好多了 今早乘头班车去伦敦了
Oh, quite. Off to London in the first train this morning.
是生意上的事吧
Business, I expect.
没错
That's right.
欧尼斯特一度对金融很有兴趣
Ernest once took a great interest in finantial matters.
就是有点过头了 是吧 夫人
Yes, got a bit ahead of myself, didn't I, ma'am?
他曾未经人同意就拿别人的钱投资
He used to invest other people's money without their permission.
看得出来 你是个园艺能手
You have green fingers, I see.
谢谢夸奖 很高兴能派上用场
Thank you. And happily free to use them.
这里湖光山色 还有这么漂亮的园子
Lakeside view, a excellent piece of garden.
没有比这更好的休闲地点了
Can't think a more pleasant place to telax on.
你这么一说 我都想加入你们了
Put like that, I feel I might join you.
这边的大门永远都是敞开的
Well, there's always room for one more.
塞罗科尔德太太
Mrs. Serrocold?
乔莉什么事
Jolly?
有一位绅士要见您
There's a gentleman to see you.
我马上就来
I'll be along in a moment.
克里斯提安
Christian!
不是你想见的人对吧
Not whom you were expecting?
我不知道你要来
I didn't know.
你还是老样子 总是神神秘秘的
Wrapped as you were, in such mistery!
胡说 我昨晚跟刘易斯说过了
Nonsense. I told Lewis last night.
他没告诉你吗
Didn't he tell you?
也许吧
Oh, perhaps he did.
我让乔莉给你安排奇尔・哈迪的房间
I'll get Jolly to prepare Kier Hardie's room.
简 很抱歉
Oh, Jane, I'm so sorry.
我来跟你介绍克里斯提安
Allow me to present Christian.
我的另一个继子
My other stepson,
他父亲是我已故的第一任丈夫
by way of my late and beloved first husband.
我明白了 虽然有点复杂
I see. Well, I think I do.
女士
Madam.
我希望你这次不会那么快离开
I hope you don't deserting us too soon this time.
至少呆到周末好吗
At least stay for the weekend?
我来这儿是打算跟刘易斯谈事情的
I was hoping to have a word with Lewis.
都是生意上的事 很乏味的
Business matter. All very tedious.
他现在不在 那你干脆愉快地留下吧
Well, he's not here, so you'll jolly have to wait!
恭敬不如从命
So much the better.
来 我们带你看看园子去
Come, let us show you the garden.
今天天气多好啊
Such a lovely day.
他们应该跟我商量一下的
They might have consulted me.
罗森先生
Mr. Lawson!
我是塞罗科尔德先生的私人秘书
I'm Mr. Serrocold's p-personal secretary,
所以 如果事情真的这么紧急
so, Gulbrandsen should have come to me,
古尔布兰德森应该来问我的
if it's all so urgent.
没错
Indeed.
他们把我当傻瓜
They take me for a fool.
但是我已经知道了 那才是重点
But I know. That's the point.
你知道什么
What do you know?
他是恶魔附身
He has the devil in him.
谁 古尔布兰德森先生还是...你父亲
Who? Mr. Gulbrandsen or... your father?
你等着瞧吧
Just you wait and see.
别烦她
Leave her alone.
你在监视我吗
Spying on me?
看不出这位老夫人想安静会儿吗 快走开
Can't you see the old dame wants some peace? Go on and splt.
这就走
Gladly.
你手上拿的是咖啡吗
Is that coffee you have there?
能给我喝一点吗 压压惊
Perhaps you could spare a drop. My nerves!
这咖啡很浓
I make it pretty strong.
我就喜欢喝浓咖啡
Well, that's the way I like it.
来一杯乔[咖啡] 你们美国人是这么说的吗
A cup of Joe. Isn't that the way you Americans call it?
还只是电影里这么演
Or is that just for the pictures?
我有时候很好奇
You know, I sometimes wonder
乔到底是个人 还是什么东西
who or what Joe is.
不管他是谁 但愿上帝保佑他
Well ... God bless him, whoever he is.
干杯
Cheers.
每当从这儿看出去 看到这些景象
You know, when I look out, on all this,
我就有点想念我的紫菀园
I begin to feel a little homesick for my asters.
我也有同感
You and me, both.
你也种紫菀吗
You have asters?
不是 我...
Oh, no, I... hmm.
你是指思乡
Homesick.
是的
Yeah.
思乡只有一种解药
Well, there's only one known cure for that.
小公主才不会懂这些
Try telling that to princess.
我能给她什么呢
What have I got to give her?
你好 这里是斯托尼盖特
Hello. Stonygates.
很好 先生
Very good, sir.
不用了 我已经通知过园丁了
There's no need. I've already indormed the groundsman.
我会亲自确认的 再见
I'll see to it myself. Goodbye.
是塞罗科尔德先生吗
Was that Mr. Serrocold?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
他会如预计的四点二十七分到家
He'll be home in the 04:27, as planned.
也许我可以开车去车站接他
Perhaps I might drive up and meet him from the station?
他想走着回来
He prefers to walk.
很好 贝耶维小姐
Very good ... Miss Bellever.
我去看看晚饭准备好了没
I should see about dinner.
马普尔小姐
Miss Marple.
古尔布兰德森先生
Oh! Mr. Gulbrandsen!
我刚想去休息一会
Just off for a little lie down.
那么别因为我搅了您的雅兴
Well, don't let me keep you.
马普尔小姐 您已经认识卡莉・路易斯...
Miss Marple, you've known Carrie-Louise ...
大半辈子了 真是难以置信啊
Oh, most of my life, would you believe?
你觉得她怎么样
How do you find her?
永远的理想主义者
As great an idealist as ever.
也许是因为
Maybe she does not
她还没有领教过世事的残酷
appreciate the evil there is in the world
跟我说说 她健康情况如何
Tell me, how is her health?
我看起来觉得挺好
She seems to me well enough.
就是有点关节炎
Appart from the arthritis.
她的心脏呢
And her heart?
她的心脏够强壮吗
Is her heart strong?
很强壮 古尔布兰德森先生
As far as one can tell, Mr Gulbrandsen.
晚饭时再见
Until supper time.
祝您睡眠愉快
Enjoy your... shut eye.
希望卡莉・路易斯不会知道...
Let's hope to spare Carrie Louise from knowledge ...
如果她太激动的话...因为她...
If it could be carried away from her... because of her ...
不是吧
Oh, dear.
就是这样 不 不 不 继续往那边
That's it. No, no, no, keep going.
往中间一点 就是那儿
More into the center. Left in there.
再往前点
Further.
抱歉 姑娘
Sorry, old girl.
蜜儿 我还以为你不喜欢这种事呢
Oh, Mil! I thought you didn't approve of such things.
万事都有头一回嘛
Try anything once.
大概吧
I bet.
克里斯提安 我希望你能留下来看彩排
Christian, I hope you'll stay for the dress rehearsal.
我有点累了
I'm a little weary.
能送纸和打印机到我房间吗
Could I have some paper and a typewriter brought up to my room?
当然可以 贝耶维小姐
Of course. Miss Bellever?
我马上去办
I'll see to it at once.
多美好啊 我们大家齐聚一个屋檐下
How nice. All of us together under the same roof.
没错
Yes.
要是还有什么我能帮上忙的...
Oh, if there's anything more I can do ...
你好好坐着 等下配合入戏就好了
You sit tight and weep like a black sheep.
好吧
Oh. All right.
准备好了吗
All set?
还没到你出场呢
Ooh! That's not your cue!
可我已经出来了 那就开始吧
Well, I'm here now. Let's go on with it.
说话专业点
Spoken like a "pro".
夫人 你忘了你的奎宁水了
Madam, you forgot your tonic.
等一等
Oh, hang on.
这活儿一般是我来干的
I normally do this.
不好意思 亲爱的 我都忘了
I'm sorry, my darling. I've quite forgotten.
没关系的
Oh! It doesn't matter.
手滑了
Butter fingers.
没事的 刘易斯 真的 小事情
It doesn't matter, Lewis. Really, it's not important.
没关系 乔莉 拿下去 我等会儿再喝
Never mind, Jolly, put it down. I'll take it later.
我想起来了 马普尔小姐
Oh, I wonder, Miss Marple?
什么事
What?
你可不可以...
I wonder, if you wouldn't mind...
我好像没带眼镜
W-well, I don- I don't seem to have my glasses.
你头上不就是吗
On your head?
是的
No. Oh! Yes, it is.
大家都等着呢
Hang on with it!
我跋山涉水...
I have travelled far and wide ...
来...
.. to ...
我想应该是"来膜拜你"
I believe it's "to hail you".
"来膜拜你..."
"to hail you ..."
来膜拜你...我们部落最伟大的神明
To hail you... to the great gods of our tribe.
饶了我吧
Dear me.
他们说 我 伟大的族长
They say that I, Big Chief Running Bear,
必须为了我的所爱 勇敢起来
must brave all ... for the love of my dear.
应该是"第三个也是最好的" 刘易斯
"Third and finest", Lewis?
什么
What?
第三个也是最好的
Third and finest.
没错 抱歉 抱歉
Oh! Oh, quite. Sorry. Sorry.
为了我第三个也是最好的妻子 夏日雨
My third and finest squaw, Summer Rain.
吉娜 你看起来太可爱了
Oh, Gina, you look lovely!
神哪
Good grief!
我们开始了
Here we go.
她美丽的眼睛 是欢欣的所在
Her beauties eyes most pleasantly framed.
太棒了 你太有才了 斯蒂维
Oh, bravo! Most eloquent, Stevie.
艾德加 艾德加
Edgar? Edgar!
坐下
Sit down.
怎么又这样
Oh! Not again!
电路故障
Wires on the blink.
- 我去检查保险丝 - 好样的 瓦利
- I'll go and check the fuse box. - Good man, Wally.
现在做什么
Well, what now?...
我们可以继续吗 大师
Shall we carry on, maestro, or er ...?
- 当心点 - 看路 艾迪
- Careful! - Steady, Eddie!
- 有什么问题吗 艾德加 - 你还敢问我
- Something wrong, Edgar? - You dare to ask me that?
- 别装得事不关己... - 他有枪
- Calm as you like, when... - He's got a gun!
- 只是个玩具 - 他在演戏
- It's just a toy. - He's playing.
我引起你们的注意了吧 大家都注意了
I've got your attention, everybody? Everybody focused?
别玩了 老兄 今晚的演出够多了
Come on, old man, it's enough theatrics for one night.
我要知道真相 我要剩下的人作证
I want the truth! And I want you all by witness.
# 见证人 见证人 #
By witness, by witness
别弹了 我是认真的
Be quiet, I'm serious.
斯蒂文 你别捣乱了
Stephen, that really isn't helping!
你吓到我们了
Ok, you're scaring us now.
看看你 可怜巴巴地站在那
Look at you! Just standing, you're pathetic!
谁去把瓦利叫来
Will somebody please, get Wally?
围着你的怪念头瞎忙活
Chasing your every whim  your every whim ...
他把门给锁了
He's gone and locked the bloody door!
把枪放下 艾德加
Put the gun down, Edgar.
点头哈腰 赔笑脸
A nod here, a smile there,
"谢谢您 塞罗科尔德先生"
"Thank you, Mr Serrocold!"
艾德加
Edgar!
"要多少糖 塞罗科尔德先生"
"How many sugars, Mr Serrocold?"
"茶够甜了吗 塞罗科尔德先生"
"Tea, sweet enough for you, Mr Serrocold?"
- 谁快阻止他 - 别犯傻 他无恶意
- Somebody do something! - Don't be silly. He's harmless.
你怎么知道
How can you say that?
别站在那光说话
Don't you just stand there, with your mouth.
把枪给我
Give me that gun!
- 都别动 - 罗森先生
- Nobody move! - Mr. Lawson.
你不觉得进来更舒服些吗
Don't you think that you might be more comfortable inside?
都别动
Nobody move!
一直以来都是你窃窃私语 两面三刀
All this time it was you, the whispering, the plotting!
- 艾德加 别发疯了 - 你答应会帮我的
- Edgar, please,this is madness. - You promised to help me!
- 艾德加 够了 - 还要骗我
- Edgar, enough! - More to fool me, hey?
谁都不相信 至少不信你们这帮...
Never trust anyone, at least not in this den of...
瞧你们
Look at you!
你们都该送去改造
They ought to send a lot of you out of this precious little fecility
看你们怎么...
and see how you...
我说了别动
I told you not to move!
- 过来 过来 - 没事了 艾德加
- Come here! Come here! - It's all right, Edgar.
- 跪下 跪下 - 我不会伤害你的
- On your knees! On your knees! - I'm not going to hurt you.
跪下
On your knees!
刘易斯
Lewis!
好疼啊
That hurt!
抓到你了 快放下枪 放下枪
Got you! Come on, drop it, drop it!
好了 闹剧结束了
There we are. The Show is over!
艾德加 钥匙拿来
Edgar! The key.
只是小打小闹 是吧
Not exactly a big game, is it?
我看他就是欺软怕硬的主
But I suppose you can always try boiling him over to a stop.
- 父亲 - 斯蒂文
- Father? - Stephen!
他来这干嘛
What's he doing here?
刘易斯・塞罗科尔德 很高兴见到你 老兄
Lewis Serrocold? Glad to meet you, old man.
艾德加 下次再这样 直接去找马弗里克医生
Oh, Edgar, whatever next? Search for Dr. Maverick, will you?
谁开枪了
Did I hear gunshots?
你一定是...
So you must be...
大首领约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克
Big Chief Johnny Restarick.
刚从苏豪区和加里克的猎场乘兴而来
Fresh from the happy hunting grounds of Soho and Garrick.
女主人的前任枕边人
And former tenant of the great white bed.
能来点润喉的吗 老兄
Any chance of something moist in a glass, old man?
当然
Why not?
瞧你 我的波提切利天使
Ha! Look at you, my Botticelli angel!
我们要报警
We have to call the police.
没必要 艾德加也平静下来了
Oh! There's no need to fuss. Edgar is quite himself again.
刘易斯也没事 是吧 亲爱的
And Lewis is fine. Aren't you, darling?
我说的不是塞罗科尔德先生
It wasn't Mr. Serrocold I was thinking of.
他总是很注重仪表
He was always so precise about his appearance.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
谁会如此狠毒
How could anyone do such a thing?
抱歉 卡莉・路易斯 但你知道
Forgive me, Carrie Louise, but had you any idea that
今晚你前夫会来吗
your former husband was coming to Stonygates tonight?
约翰尼
Johnny?
是的 你怎么知道
Yes. How did you know?
早些 亲爱的 我们在温室旁时
Earlier, dear, when we were near the glasshouse,
你试图告诉我你的烦恼
you tried to tell me what was troubling you.
是这样的...
Yes, you see...
约翰尼总是像追求者一样
..Johnny kept writing me these long letters,
给我写情书
like some supplicant at the gate,
如果我拒绝他 他就没完
threatening to end it all, if I turned him away.
- 你给过他希望吗 - 绝没有
- And you gave him hope? - Never!
但天知道刘易斯会怎么想
Though heaven knows what Lewis will make of it.
每当他在报纸上看到约翰尼的名字
He gets into the most deadful huff
他都会吃干醋
if he so much sees Johnny's name in the newspaper.
- 塞罗科尔德夫人 - 请进
- Mrs. Serrocold? - Do come in.
克里探长 夫人 这是我的助理莱克警官
Inspetor Curry, ma'm. My assistent, sargeant Lake.
- 死者是你的继子吧 - 是的
- Your stepson, I gather. - That's right.
是我已故第一任丈夫的儿子
About my late first husband.
这么晚了还发生这可怕的噩耗
Dreadful shock, a bit of a late night, I imagine.
简・马普尔 塞罗科尔德夫人的朋友
Jane Marple. Friend of Mrs. Serrocold.
给夫人搬个椅子来 警官
Chair for the lady, Sargeant.
先讲我了解到的情况
So... let's see if I got this straight.
死者今天到达来找你丈夫
The deceased arrived today
刘易斯・塞罗科尔德先生
on a pressing matter of business
商讨生意上的要紧事
with your husband, Mr. Lewis Serrocold.
死者用过少许晚餐后 回房休息
The deceased then retired to his room after a light supper,
然后背部被刺...
where he was stabbed in the back...
与此同时 其他人都被锁在楼下客厅
..while the rest of the company were busy downstairs,locked
看戏剧表演 其间艾德加・罗森先生
in the drawing room, for a theatrical performance that went a riot
出来闹过事
on account of a Mr... Edgar Lawson.
是这样的
That's correct.
那个你无需担心 探长先生 是一段小插曲
Nothing to concern you there, inspector. A momentary aberration.
艾德加・罗森是你这里的犯人之一吗
One of your convicts, hey, this Edgar Lawson?
- 什么意思 - 他是什么人
- What of it? - What's he in for?
明白了
Oh, I see.
艾德加只是幻想
Edgar rather pressed his atention
他和社会名流有关系
on one or two pillars of
丘吉尔先生 蒙哥马利子爵等等
society. Mr. Churchill... Viscount Montgomery, and so on...
他和我们在一起两年了 已经有了很大的进步
He's been with us two years. He's made great strides.
他可以进入枪械室吗
And he had access to the gun room?
艾德加是我丈夫的私人助理
Edgar is my husband's personal secretary.
我明白了
I see.
我们经常会雇佣劳教人员
From time to time, we employ individuals from the facility.
承担更多的责任使他们受益
Those who'd benefict from added responsability.
罗森先生现在在哪
Where is he now, this Mr. Lawson?
睡了 马弗里克医生给他打了镇定剂
Asleep. Dr. Maverick sedated him.
- 其他犯人呢 - 在安全的宵禁
- And were the other convicts? - Safely under curfew.
庄园的所有大门 下午五点会准时锁上
All the gates of the property are locked at 05:00PM sharp.
当然
Of course.
这个...就是杀人凶器了
This er... would be the murder weapon, then.
像是军用的
Military flavour.
认识吗
Familiar at all?
它是...曾是瓦利・哈德先生的
It belonged... belongs to a Mr. Wally Hudd.
美国军用刀
US... Army knife.
那个去外面修电路的美国人吗
The American who left the locked room to fix the wire?
他把刀放在自己房里
He kept that knife in his room.
谁都有可能拿走它
Absolutely anybody could have taken it.
我想现场证据我们收集得差不多了
I think we've cleaned as much as we can from the crime scene.
让吉娜到我房里去
I'd like Gina to see me to my room.
吉娜小姐
Miss Gina!
探长先生 抱歉
Oh, Inspector. I'm sorry.
我对这台打字机很好奇
I did wonder... The typewriter.
它是帝国好伴侣牌的
Uh...It's an Imperial Good Companion
除非是我糊涂了
Unless I have my evenings muddled, I...
但我记得去世的古尔布兰德森先生
I seem to recall that late Mr. Gulbrandsen
要求过把打印机和纸送到这房间
requested a typewriter and paper to be brought up to this room?
是的 没错
Yes, that's right.
这就让我很奇怪
It struck me as a little odd,
既然他要写信件
one would imagine he wished to write correspondence,
为什么 这里什么都没有
only...it doesn't appear to be any.
- 贝耶维小姐 - 之前的确有封信在这
- Miss Bellever? - As a matter of fact, there was a letter.
我想我说过谁都不能动现场
I thought I told no one to tuch a thing.
谁还来过这
Who was up in here?
只有刘易斯・塞罗科尔德先生
Only Mr. Lewis Serrocold.
非常好
Very good.
谢谢 多谢 您是...
Thank you. Thank you, Miss hum...
马普尔 不客气
Marple. Quite welcome.
- 还察觉到什么吗 - 没特别的了
- Anything else up your sleeve? - Not especially.
当然还有一件小事
Just a little thing, of course,
较早之前我和古尔布兰德森先生谈过话
but after my conversation with Mr. Gulbrandsen earlier in the day
你和受害者说过话吗
You spoke with the victim?
只是简单交流了下
Only briefly, I'm affraid.
但他说了些不寻常的话
But he said something rather unusual.
他询问过卡莉・路易斯的健康问题
He asked out of Carrie Louise's health.
"她的心脏是否强壮"
"Is her heart strong?"
- 她的心脏 - 这是他的原话
- Her heart? - Those were his words.
他是什么意思呢
What did he mean by that?
或许刘易斯・塞罗科尔德更了解
Peraps Lewis Serrocold can shed more light on the matter.
今晚他们在公园里聊了天
They were having a talk this evening in the park.
我凑巧瞄了眼窗外
I just happened to be looking out of my window.
你是个查案老手 是吧 马普尔小姐
You are not new to this game, are you, Miss.. Marple..?
看看这个
Look at this.
"我 大首领酋长
"I, Big Chief Running Bear,
必须为我所爱 勇往直前..."
must brave all for the love of..."
谁写的这傻东西
Who wrote this drivel?
其实是我写的
I did, as a matter of fact.
不用担心 给我一只笔
Ah, not to worry. Gimme a pencil,
看我怎样把它化腐朽为神奇
we'll see if we can turn this around.
不 这剧本很好 不用你操心
No! We're very good as we are, thanks all the same.
- 我觉得也还好 - 那我认错了
- I think it's jolly good. -Well, I stand corrected.
我们该睡觉了吧
Oh, hello, is that the time?
我说 你可以给以前的老伙计
I say, you couldn't free the Oktober Suite
施舍间房吧
for a former comrade, could you?
- 不能睡这里 - 没得选择 老兄
- He's not sleeping in here. - No choice, old man.
- 警察的命令 - 好吧
- Copper's orders. - Very well.
我们的贫民窟里还是有房间可以招待的
I dare say that we can accomodate the gentleman in Skid Row.
这才够意思嘛
That's more like is.
贝耶维小姐 把我们的客人带去劳教工厂
Miss Bellever, will you deliver our guest to the facility?
谢谢 什么
Thank you... What?!
我相信那里的房间会满足你的需要
I'm sure you'll find the accomodation adequate to your needs.
两件事都没错
Quite correct on both counts.
晚饭前我和克里斯提安谈过
Christian and I did speak before dinner.
打字机上也的确有信
And there was indeed a letter in the typewriter.
信在我这
Ah!... I have it with me now.
我很鄙视随便动我证物的人
I take a dim view, sir, of those who tamper with my evidence.
当然
Of course you do.
但我知道我妻子会去看她继子的遗体
But you see, I knew my wife wanted to view her late stepson's body,
我不想让她瞥见信的内容
and if she got a glimpse to... letter's contents...
听起来很严重啊 先生
All sounds very grave, sir.
生意上的事有什么...
Why a matter of businees could be so...
跟生意上的事没关系
It has nothing to do with business!
- 你们是同事 - 某种程度上是
- Well, you were colleagues. - In some way.
克里斯提安・古尔布兰德森和我
Christian Gulbrandsen was a fellow Trustee
还有我妻子的妹妹
of his late father's estate
是他父亲遗产的受托人
together with myself and my wife's sister,
鲁思・凡・赖多克 她很有商业头脑
Ruth van Rydock. A sound head for business.
总之 我管理日常资金的运转
Anyway I take care of day-to-day running.
我懂点审计
I have a background in auditiing.
我们三个至少每年见一面
The three of us like to meet,
一起查账
at least once a year, to keep an eye on the accounts.
上一次我们见的时候
When we last met,
克里斯提安说了一些他的担忧
Christian outlined some concerns ....
但他比以前都谨慎 在没查清真相之前
Mas, ever cautious, he did not round to specifics,
他没有透露具体的细节
not until he made inquiries.
他想确定了再说 而今晚...
He wanted to be sure, you see. And tonight...
他终于说出了真相
..He finally confessed the truth.
我们决定 他需要马上写信给鲁思征求意见
We agreed that he should write to Ruth at once and seek her advice.
就是这个 你看吧
There, there! Read it.
"亲爱的鲁思
"Dear Ruth ...
我们将要面对一场严重的危机
.. A crisis of extraordinary gravity has risen
我迷失其中 不知如何应对"
and I'm at a lost in how to deal with it. "
"我了解你对卡莉・路易斯有深切的感情
"I know how your deep affection is for Carrie Louise,
你关心一切会影响到她的事物
how grave your concern for anything that affects her.
直接了当地说 我有理由相信
Not to beat about the bush, I have reason to believe
她正在被人慢慢地下药毒害
she is being slowly and cold-bloodedly poisoned.
我的第一次怀疑是在..."
I first suspected this when ... "
这里就中断了
And here he breaks off.
那时他被杀了
He was murdered.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
我每天和她生活在一起
Only living with her, "in and out of each other's pockets",
看不出有什么变化
one doesn't see the little changes.
你觉得克里斯提安・古尔布兰德森
And you think that Christian Gulbrandsen
知道是谁下的毒吗
knew the identity of the poisoner?
他应该有一点想法 要是我多问问他就好了
He had an idea. If only I had pressed him.
我想告诉你 马普尔小姐
I wanted you to know, Miss Marple,
你是我妻子的老朋友了
as an old friend of my wife's.
谢谢 谢谢大家
Thank you. To all of you.
你也认为她完全没有
You agree, it's imperative
察觉到危机吧
she discovers no hint of this threat?
如果一个女人处于危险的处境
If the woman's in danger,
她需要了解自己的危机
she needs to be aware of the risk.
但谁会想要伤害卡莉・路易斯呢
But who would wish harm on Carrie Louise?
她可是一位受众人尊敬的女人
A woman so universally admired.
会有什么陷害她的动机呢
What possible motive?
当时客厅的大多数房门都锁着
Well, most of the house were locked in the drawing room,
塞罗科尔德先生正被艾德加・罗森用枪指着
Mr. Serrocold here with a gun pointed by the harmless Edgar Lawson
那看起来嫌疑人范围便缩小了
Yes, that would seem to narrow the field.
请让我... 谢谢
If I could just ...thanks.
就像我说的 我直接来到这里
Like I told you, I came straight here.
这些要命的英国电线
The er... crazy british wiring,
保险丝盒被烧了 已经是那晚上的第二次了
the fuse box was burned, the second time that night.
- 第二次吗 - 是啊 有人这么告诉我的
- Second, sir? - Yeah. That's what I've told.
大约七点的时候停了一次电
The lights went off about seven o'clock.
你能解释一下为何你的刀
Can you explain what your knife
会在死者的背上吗 先生
was doing in that fellow's back, sir?
那刀放在我们的卧室
I... well, it was in our bedroom,
床边桌子的第二个抽屉 任何人都可以拿到
second drawer, bedside table. Anybody could have taken it.
任何人
Anybody.
你相信他的话吗
Do you believe him?
我一向对美国人都没有太多同情
I never had much sympathy toward americans.
至少这个人在战争的时候尽本职了
At least this one did his bit in the war.
- 屋里的工作人员呢 - 晚上放假
- What about house staff? - Night off.
前夫呢 约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克
The ex-husband? Johnny Restarick?
我认为是他做的 一定是他做的
I think it was him, sir. It has to be.
他是唯一一个没有合理解释的人 不是吗先生
He's the only other person who's unaccounted for. Right, sir?
我想我们还能找到更多线索
I think we can do better than that.
不要只看表面 莱克警官
Never underestimate the power of the obvious, sergeant Lake.
- 先生 - 这些笼中之鸟
- Sir? - Flotted jailbirds,
内心迂腐 燃烧着内心的愤怒
rotten to the core, simmering in their own juices.
江山易改本性难移 莱克警官
The leopard don't change it's spots, sergeant Lake,
在西部巴克斯也一样
not in West Bucks.
说得好 先生
Certainly well drawed, Sir.
看起来 他们每天早上都这样训练
Apparently, they do training like this, every morning.
为了什么训练呢
Training for what?
他在那里做什么
What's he doing here?
刘易斯・塞罗科尔德的命令
Lewis Serrocold's orders.
他对比赛又不感兴趣 来吧
Not keen on the competition, hey? Come on.
雷斯塔瑞克先生 能否说句话
Sr. Restarick. A word, if you please.
如果你问我 刘易斯只是想仔细看看
If you ask me, Lewis wants a closer look.
这些大城市的官员就和神圣的牧师一样
I mean, these city suits, are just glorified clerks,
从西方赶来 周五的夜晚
coming from the west,Friday night, you know.
一副道貌岸然的样子 拜托
Butter wouldn't melt in his mouth. Oh, please,
以为我看不出来吗
I've seen it dribbling down his chin.
- 你为什么要来斯托尼盖特 - 因为爱情
- What brought to Stonygates? - Love gave me wings.
我可要保持身材
Got to get fit, you see.
为了塞罗科尔德夫人吗
For Mrs. Serrocold?
每个人都应该得到第二次机会 不是吗
Look, everybody is entitled to a second chance, aren't they?
- 除了杀人犯 - 老天
- Except for muderers. - Oh, please.
所以你从火车站走过来 穿过公园
So, you came walking from the station, proceeded through the park,
去到了房子的后院 是这样吗 先生
til the back of the main house. Is this correct, sir?
我最有嫌疑是吗 独自一人 没有证人
Perfect suspect, aren't I? Quite alone, no witnesses.
请问先生在你走到房子的路上
Seen anything, sir,
有看到什么吗
on your way round to the house?
我以一种非常疯狂且独特的方式出场了
Now, I did one of my mad, criative turns.
我并不指望你能理解
Here, I wouldn't expect you to understand that.
- 你怎么可能会理解呢 - 可以试着理解
- How could you? - I might.
那晚雾很大
Well, it was the fog that got me going,
黑暗之中 我站在花园里
standing there, in the darkness of the garden.
听到了脚步声 然后是枪声
Footsteps. And then the gun.
我当时便想
And I thought to myself: now that's
这样的效果完全可以用在莱姆豪斯之夜
exactly the effect that I want for my Limehouse Nights.
- 我的芭蕾舞剧 - 脚步声吗
- My ballet? - Footsteps?
- 哪边来的 - 分辨不出来 老伙计
- Where from? - Impossible to say, old man.
所以你是穿过花园走到了落地窗前
So, you crossed the garden to the french windows.
是啊 好奇要去看看
Yeah. Yes. Well, fancied to a closer look.
有什么问题吗
Anything wrong with that?
我怪我自己
I blame myself.
克里斯提安死了
Christian dead,
现在又是吉娜她那年轻的美国小伙
and now Gina's young american.
你觉得瓦利可能是杀人犯吗
You think Wally might have committed the murder?
我也不知道
I don't know what to think.
但有时候我很疑惑
But sometimes I wonder.
她如此匆忙地结婚
The way she rushed into the marriage,
是不是为了得到母亲的注意
was it for want of a mother's affection?
我真不应该花这么多时间在工作上
If I'd been less consumed with my own work.
而是花更多的时间和精力在她身上
If I'd given more time, or more energy.
小孩都需要被关怀 被爱护 不是吗
A child needs to feel cherished in the nursery, doesn't she?
不然她便一直不知道自己存在的意义
Or she'll never come to know her own value.
更何况 还是领养的小孩
Above all, an adopted child.
什么声音
What was that?
不 看
Oh, no, look!
停下来 警察
Stop! Police!
停下来
Stop!
警察
Police!
瓦利
Wally!
Oh! Oh, Wally!
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
我们到了吗
Are we there?
这真是荒谬 你们应该立刻叫我过来
This is monstrous! I should have been summoned at once!
我是受托人 我有权利
I am a Trustee. I have rights.
如果有人想要杀我的姐姐...
And if someone is trying to kill my sister ...
恐怕这不是"如果" 我刚收到了确认的电报
No "if" about that, I'm affraid. I just received a telegram confirming
塞罗科尔德夫人的药中含有砒霜
the presence of arsenic in Mrs. Serrocold's bottle of tonic.
那我们应该立刻告诉她
Then we must tell her at once!
我的老天 鲁思
For pete's sake, Ruth!
先等到明天我们做好准备 以防万一好吗
Keep your powder dry until the morning, will ya?
真是奇怪
Oh, how perfectly quaint!
难怪你们国家会输掉整个王国
No wonder you people have lost the Empire.
杀人犯仍在逍遥法外
There's a killer on the loose!
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
每次她拿起勺子送到嘴边
You think I don't hold my breath
我都心惊胆战的
every time she lifts a spoon to her lips?
我也在尽最大的努力保护我的妻子
I'm trying to protect my wife as lovingly as I can.
你为她太小题大做了 一直都是这样
You're making too much fuss of her. You always have.
哈德先生情况怎么样了
How is Mr. Hudd fairing?
我们随时都可以把他带走 女士
Oh, we'll have him off your in no time, ma'am
只要等他可以移动就好
just as soon as he's fit to move.
我怎么知道他在想什么
How would I know what he's been up to?
他要做什么 我怎么知道
How would I know the first thing about him?
我只是他的妻子
I'm only his wife, after all!
对不起 房间很乱
Sorry. Such mess.
在抽屉某处找到的
Found this in a drawer, somewhere.
虽然我没有仔细想 但看起来像是预谋好的
It's the er... air of contriver, as I don't care for.
什么
What?
我只是在想 这一切都那么巧合
Well, I was just thinking how convenient it all was,
我们安全地被困在了客厅
there we were in the drawing room, safely under locking key,
而碰巧这时候...
preciselly the moment when ...
我明白你的意思
I get it your point.
但如果没有别的地方可以出去...
But if there was no other way out ...
瓦利 不
Wally! No!
吉娜 吉娜
Gina? Gina!
你们不能带走他 不能带走他
Don't you dare, gents! Don't you dare!
放开他
Get away from them!
放开 我不会让你们带走他的
Get away! I won't let you ...
你们不能带走他
You can't take him away.
我有很重要的事要告诉探长
I've got something very important to tell the Inspector!
这真是新鲜事
What fresh air is this, hey?
给
Here, take.
- 别闹 别闹 吉娜 - 放开
- Please, please, Gina! - Let go!
- 放开他 - 别闹了 吉娜
- Come! Leave him! - Gina, please!
冷静点 你这是在帮倒忙
Calm down, please. This isn't helping at all.
- 他什么都没做 - 先进来
- He hasn't done anything! - Come inside.
好了 年轻的小姐 你想要给我们看什么
Now, young lady, what was it you wanted to show us?
我们任何一个人都能离开这房间
Anyone of us could have left this room
去杀那可怜的克里斯提安
to murder poor Christian.
那儿 看到了吗
There, you see?
进吧 莱克警官 进来吧
Come on, sargeant Lake. Come on.
去吧
Go on.
这边来 探长先生
This way, Inspector.
来
Come.
她去哪儿了
Where does she go?
先生 有火柴
Sir, look. Matches.
- 最近的吗 - 应该是的
- Recents? - I should say.
很奇怪的味道
Interesting smell.
- 柴油吗 - 有可能
- Diesel? - Possibly.
看到了吗 探长先生
So, you see, Inspector,
我们任何一个人都有嫌疑
any of us could have done it.
这真是荒谬 罗森先生一开始表演
That's absurd. Once Mr. Lawson started firing,
我们全都在原地不动
we were all frozen to the spot.
没有人动过吗
Nobody moved?
哈德先生离开的期间 所有人都在场吗
Everyone present and correct throughout Mr. Hudd's absence?
- 我要你们成为我的见证人 - 是的
- And I want all of you to be my witnesses. - Absolutely.
但那时候停电了
But the lights were out.
那我也看见了
I know what I saw.
斯蒂文吗
Stephen?
他在弹琴 我叫他停下来
He was lurking at the piano. I told him not.
斯蒂文 你这是在帮倒忙
Stephen, that really isn't helping.
不是 斯蒂文跑去帮忙了
No, no. Stephen went for help.
这些日子 帮你写信
All these weeks writing your letters.
他出去时把门锁了
He's gone and locked the bloody door!
那...他在那儿之后去哪儿了
And er ... where did he go after that?
我也不清楚
I couldn't honestly say.
那年轻的哈德夫人呢
And young Mrs. Hudd?
吉娜吗
Gina?
她和我一起 就在其他人身后
She was with me, just behind the others.
你确定吗
You quite certain of that fact?
你这一问...
Well, now that you press me ...
她从窗户那边走过来
.. She came away from the window ...
请把瓦利叫过来
Will somebody, please, get Wally?
穿着那可笑的衣服
.. in that preposterous outfit,
可那之后...
but then ...
你是在怀疑我妹妹...
You don't think my sister could ...
我们目前还没有任何结论
Now, we are not jumping to any conclusions.
她这人一直都非常轻浮 反复无常
Well, she's always been flighty. Unpredictable, volatile.
自从她来了这里以后 便一直粘着妈妈
And she's sticking to mamma like fly-paper since the moment she got here.
米尔德里德吗
What, Mildred?
她撞倒了那张小桌子
Well, she knocked in that little table.
那之后 我就不知道她去哪儿了
After that, I don't know where's she gone to.
那请问 探长先生
So, now, Inspector
你不会再逮捕瓦利了吧
you're not really going to arrest my Wally, are you?
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing out here?
闻到了吗
Smell that?
大红木
Giant red-wood.
美国的味道
Smells of America.
这宝贝是我在这儿唯一能信任的东西了
This baby is about the last thing in this damn place I can count in.
别这么伤感
Don't be so melodramatic
还有 这"宝贝"是巨杉 不是红木
anyway, this "baby" is a Wellingtonia, not redwood.
- 没有区别 - 瓦利
- Makes no difference. - Wally.
瓦利 你骑着自行车要去哪里
Wally, where were you going in that bicycle?
留下我怎么办
What about me?
- 亲爱的 你在做什么 - 干活
- Darling, what're you doing? - Keeping busy.
他又蛮不讲理了吗
Oh, has he been a brut again?
- 他没有蛮不讲理 - 当然啦
- He's not a brut. - Of course not.
但他那样一个人 在你这样的姑娘面前
But a chap like that, And a gal like you,
他怎么会知道你想要什么
he doesn't know what makes you tick.
- 他怎么知道 - 我想要什么
- How could he? - What makes me tick?
镇里的公寓
A flat in town.
装满漂亮衣服的衣柜
A wardrobe heaving with pretty clothes.
和一个爱干净的大眼情人
And a cow-eyed lover who doesn't leave crums in the bed.
没错吧
Am I right?
你一点都不了解我
You don't know the first thing about me.
我了解得足够多了
I know all I need.
总有一天 我会和克罗伊斯君王一样富有
One day, I'm gonna be as rich as Croesus.
只要我的话剧上演
As soon as I receive my play off.
而你 亲爱的 将会成为克罗伊斯皇后
And you, my dear, you shall be as rich as Mrs. Croesus.
嫁给我
Marry me.
傻瓜
Idiot!
你不是喜欢男人围着你转吗
You like to having men mooning after you, don't you?
是的 很残忍吧
Yes. Is it very cruel?
太残忍了
Yes. Terribly.
但是
Still...
用不了几年 我就没那魔力了
..in a few years the magic will soon wear off
没人会再关注我了
and no-one will look at me ever again.
所有人 甚至你
And everyone, even you ...
都会看到我有多堕落
.. will see how truly rotten how really am.
斯蒂文
Stephen!
你好 蜜儿
Hello, Mil.
你们怎么能
How could you?
不过我倒不惊讶
I don't know why I'm surprised.
什么事都跟吉娜有关 跟谁都有一腿
Anything goes with Gina. Or anyone.
请别说出去
Please, don't say anything.
你不会说的吧 蜜儿
You won't say anything, will you, Mil?
- 你们选的时间恶心到我了 - 时间
- It's the timing that sickens me. - Timing?
- 妈妈被人下毒了 - 什么
- Mother being poisoned. - What?
没听说吗
Ha, didn't you hear?
- 很明显是砒霜 - 别说了 蜜儿
- With arsenic, aparently. - Give it a rest, Mil.
震惊了吧
Mm... mark the air of tragic surprise.
别装无辜 小妞
Don't come with innocent with me, young lady.
我说过 血统
As I said, blood, well... out.
毒死塞罗科尔德太太 谁受益最大呢
Who had most to gain from the poisoning of Mrs. Serrocold?
如果我妻子死了
In the event of my wife's death,
房产是平分给两个女儿的
the estate is to be divided equally between our daughters,
吉娜和米尔德里德
Gina and Mildred.
还有一万美元给她的闺蜜
And, in addition $10.000 to her companion..
贝耶维小姐
Miss Bellever?
还有一万美元给小斯蒂文
And a further $10 000 for young Stephen.
每个人都有动机
No end of motive.
我可以问下你有什么好处吗 先生
And you, sir, if you don't mind my asking?
刘易斯他自己就有钱得很
Oh, Lewis is rolling in money of his own.
没有的事
Not quite, if I may put it.
遗嘱好像是最近才写的
The paperwork looks rather new.
是的 六周前我的妻子重立的
Yes. My wife had to rewritten it six weeks ago.
- 因为那场火灾吗 - 是的
- On account of the fire? - That's right.
做了什么修改
Anything altered?
加了给斯蒂文的那笔钱
only the extra funds for Stephen.
看不出什么来
I wouldn't read anything into that.
上一场音乐会搞砸了之后
I think my wife was rather concerned
我妻子就相当担心他
when its latest musical went south.
他知道吗 他知道自己会分到遗产吗
And did he know this? Did he know about the extra cash?
- 我想我妻子没告诉他 - 奇怪
- I believe my wife did tell him. - Mistifier.
你走神了 马普尔小姐
She is miles away. Miss Marple?
不好意思
I'm so sorry.
我刚刚在想艾德加・罗森的事 真的太奇怪了
I was thinking about Edgar Lawson and how very odd it was.
继续说
Go on.
我想知道他为什么针对你
I do wonder, why do turn on you,
针对一个对他比别人都好的人
the one person that has done more for him than anyone else?
为什么是那天晚上 正好是凶案发生的时候
And why that night, at the very moment of the murder?
你这么说起来 是很奇怪
Odd..., as you say.
不止这样吧
Well, it's more than that, isn't it?
他好像被人植入了一个想法
It's almost as if somebody put the idea into his idea.
有人利用了罗森容易激动的特点
Purposely knowing young Lawson would go off the deep end?
多么完美的掩饰方法啊
What a perfect cover that would be,
所有人都把注意力放在了罗森身上
everybody focused on young Lawson, specially if that somebody
特别是那人还体贴地给了罗森一把枪
had thoughtfully supplied a revolver from the gun room.
- 我不仅犯了错... - 罗森先生
- What I did wasn't just wrong, was just ... - Mr. Lawson.
不 让我说完
No, let me finish.
我背信弃义 不可原谅
It was unconscious, unforgivable.
他对我那么好
After all he did for me, was--
罗森先生 你是想铲土豆出气吗
Mr. Lawson, are you chipping those potatoes, or what?
我说了 都是我的错
As I said, the fault was on my head alone.
逮捕我吧 我不在乎
Arrest me if you like, I don't care.
冷静一下 先生
All in good time, sir.
没人和我说什么
Nobody said anything to me
不管是塞罗科尔德先生还是其他人
regarding Mr. Serrocold, or anybody else.
我就是太生气了
I just get angry and muddled.
丘吉尔先生会抑郁 我也会生气
Mr. Churchill has his black dog and I ...and I have my red mist.
没人跟你说过吗
Nobody said a word?
比如斯蒂文・雷斯塔瑞克先生也没有吗
Mr. Stephen Restarick, for instance?
没有
No!
其他人也没有吗 你真的确定吗
Nobody else? You're quite sure?
- 移情是很微妙的 - 移情
- Transference is a very slippery fish. - Transference?
简单地说
Simply put, the redirection
患者会把对亲人的认知
of the patient's experiences to some significant other  ,
转移到和他最亲近的人身上
in this case, the pater or father,
在这个案子里 就是他父亲
onto the Tabula Rasa of those closest to him.
你的意思是
All you are saying is that
艾德加・罗森把刘易斯・塞罗科尔德
Edgar Lawson came to believe that Lewis Serrocold
当成了他父亲
was his Pop?
没错 就是这意思
In a word. Yes, exactly. Mm.
可能在艾德加的想象中
Indeed, it could be that in Edgar's imagination, the pater
对父亲的憎恨
familias was more an object of rage,
远甚于崇拜
rather than worship.
其实 他常提到的那个
In fact, this "spy" of whom he constantly talks,
暗中监视诋毁他的人
always watching and whispering:
就是他失缺的父亲的化身
could simply be a representation of the absent father.
那就是说 他是个疯子
So, "round the twist", was he?
不 探长 千万别用那个词
No. Please, Inspector, never, never use that term.
而且 直到最近几周
Besides, up until the last few weeks,
艾德加进展良好
one was making great strides with Edgar.
快点 快点 欧尼斯特病得很厉害 快点
Quick, quick! Mr. Ernest is very ill. Quick!
去楼上医务室
Upstairs into the infirmary.
别让身体创伤变成精神创伤
We mustn't transform physical trauma into mental trauma,
尽力救他
whatever we do.
楼上 把他抬楼上去
Upstairs! Take him upstairs!
夫人
Madam.
这是
I say...?!
什么鬼东西
What the devil?
- 生蚝 - 生蚝
- Oysters? - Oysters.
臭了
Rotten.
- 一定是 - 难怪成那样了
- Must be. - No wonder he was off-colour.
长官
Sir!
你就是这样对待他们的吗
So... this is how you feed them water, is it?
- 他们 - 犯人们
- Them? - The convicts.
他叫欧尼斯特
His name is Ernest,
先声明 我对这些东西一点都不了解
and for the record, I have no idea of how those supplies have got in there.
我觉得是用这个
I think I could far them a guess.
看到了吧
Oh, would you look at that?
庄园里的钥匙
The keys of the kingdom.
欧尼斯特有了它就能来去自如了
Perhaps your Mr. Ernest could come and go as he pleased.
他肯定是去厨房拿了不少吃的
He must be helping himself fom the kitchen.
夫人的药也在厨房 他下了砒霜后
Or as he took a byte to eat after he slipped some arsenic into
就顺手拿了点吃的
Madam's tonic, which also can be found in the kitchen .
我想他来自惠特斯特布尔
He hails from Whitstable, I believe.
生蚝之乡
Home of oysters.
没错
Quite right.
但是在那个地方长大的人
One imagines a fellow bought up around this particular kind of food
应该一眼就看出来是不是...
would know immediately if they were...
- 坏了 - 没错
- Off? - Quite.
你是说生蚝被下毒了吗
You think the oysters were poisoned?
肯定是
Of course.
- 先生 - 是鲁思为卡莉・路易斯订的
- Sir? - Ruth ordered them for Carrie Louise.
我妻子仅有的嗜好之一
One of my wive's very few indulgences.
他们接下来还会怎么做呢
Oh, whatever will they think of next?
或许是时候和卡莉・路易斯开诚布公了
Might this be the time to break the news to Carrie Louise?
我自己家里有人想害我
Someone in my own home is seeking to poison me,
而我亲爱的克里斯提安
and my own dear Christian murdered
在说出这个人的名字之前被杀了
before he could name my enemy?
抱歉 亲爱的 瞒着你是我的主意
I'm sorry, my love, it was my decision to keep all this from you.
我就知道不太对劲 是吧 简
I knew something was up, didn't I, Jane?
- 所以你来这是... - 我委托的
- So you came here ... - On my orders.
我知道你不会同意 所以就没问你
I knew you wouldn't have agreed, so I didn't ask you.
亲爱的妹妹 你还真有先见之明
My dear sister, how very prescient!
我们只想帮点忙
We're only trying to help here!
原谅我 真希望我能早点来
Forgive me. I only wish I had come sooner.
确实
Indeed.
亲爱的欧尼斯特怎么样了
And how is dear Ernest?
神志不清 但总算是还活着
Unconscious, but alive, thank goodness.
毒药对他影响很大
The poison must work his way through it.
那倒是教他以后别再偷东西了
That will teach him to keep his thieving hands to himself.
- 前提是他活得足够长 - 得了吧 姐姐
- Provided he lives long enough. - Oh, come off it, sis!
如果你真想改变这些人
If you really wish to reform these people,
有更简单 更经济的办法
there are simpler and more economical ways to do it.
这就是你拯救破碎世界的方法
And that's your remedy for a broken world?
给他们吃砒霜吗
Let them eat arsenic?
亲爱的
Darling!
有时候我觉得她想让我做的每件事都失败
Well, sometimes, I think she wants everything I do to fall apart,
那样她就可以证明
so that she can prove
整个世界都和她一样残酷无情
the world is as savage and heartless as she is!
希望没打扰到各位
Not interrupting, I presume?
完全没有 我正准备走
Not at all, I was just leaving.
鲁思 你才刚到不久
Ruth, you've only just got in here.
夫人 我记得你为今晚的晚餐
Madam, I gather you've ordered in
订了几盒生蚝
several boxes of oysters for tonight's supper.
是的 你没看到这儿被弄得多脏吗
Yes! Have you seen the filth they serve in this place?
灰色 灰色 全是灰色
Beige! Beige! Everything's beige!
任何人都不能离开这
I would ask that nobody leave this compound.
别开玩笑了
Don't be absurd.
介意把我的包
Would you mind seeing that my bags
拿到楼下我的车里吗 谢谢了
are brought down to my car, please? Thank you.
我是个...
I'm a er ...
鲁思和卡莉・路易斯只有在远隔重洋的时候
Ruth and Carrie Louise have always been the best of sisters ...
才是最好的姐妹
providing they maintain an ocean between them.
那约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克呢
And Johnny Restarick?
他是最好的前夫吗
Is he the best of ex-husbands?
众说纷纭 有这个词吧
"The jury is out". Is that the phrase?
走吧
Shall we?
不过 要从这个戏剧性的地方
Still, it's not easy to conduct a poisoning campaign
找出谁下的毒可不是件容易的事
from the bordellos of London theatrical district
说的不错 探长先生
An excellent point, Inspector, very well made.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
突然想到
You know, it did occur to me,
我们一直在猜测嫌疑犯
that we've all been so busy, wondering if the convicts
是怎么从正门进到房子里的
could have climbed the main gate to the house
以至于我们忽略了其他门
that we lost sight of the other gate.
其他门
Other...?
这里 小屋旁
Here, by the lodge.
约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克说他穿过花园进到房子里
Johnny Restarick claims that he entered the house through the park.
这些门每天傍晚五点整就锁了
I gather these are locked every evening at five o'clock sharp.
真好奇
One wonders,
一个已过壮年的绅士
how did a gentleman,
是怎样翻过或穿过这门的呢
past his physical prime get over it or through?
除非有人帮他
Well, unless someone gave him a helping hand.
是他的儿子 斯蒂文
His son. Stephen.
我们知道他会从遗嘱中获利
We know he stands to gain from the will.
可能吧
Perhaps,
但我感觉这父子俩的关系不是那么亲密
although I don't sense any great intimacy between father and son.
那会是谁
Well, who then?
我还记得你接的那个电话
It was the phone call that struck me.
不需要 我已经通知过园丁了
There's no need. I've already informed the groundsman.
我会亲自去看一下的
I'll see to it myself.
再见
Goodbye.
- 是塞罗科尔德先生打来的吗 - 是的
- Is that Mr. Serrocold? - Yes, sir.
他会按计划在四点二十七分回家
He'll be home in the 4:27 as planned.
探长先生 我可以冒昧推测一下吗
If I may presume, Inspector?
那天你匆匆地接了一个怎样的小任务呢
What small task were you so quick to entertain, that day?
是你开的门 对吧
You were unlocking the gates, weren't you?
给塞罗科尔德先生开的吗
For Mr. Serrocold?
或者说当时那些门可能没关
Or so they might have left open,
给晚些要来的另一位访客留着
giving another visitor access to to the house, later on that night?
约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克
Johnny Restarick.
贝耶维小姐 他非常潇洒 对吗
Quite dashing in his way, isn't he, Miss Bellever?
我曾经这样觉得
I used to think so.
当然 这并不是什么大错
No great crime in that, surely
每两周 我都会去一次小镇
I'd go up to town, once a fortnight,
在我休假的时候 看一场午后演出
on my day off... catch a matinée.
我在表演结束后偶然遇到了约翰尼
I ran into Johnny after the show.
他风度翩翩
He was in his element.
相比在乡下 那个下午一切都是那么迷人
It all seemed so glamorous, after long afternoons in the country.
我应该是被迷住了
I was seduced, I supposed.
然后约翰尼开始说起卡莉・路易斯
Then, Johnny started up about Carrie Louise.
他必须要和她谈谈
He had to talk to her.
一定要告诉她
She had to be told,
否则我们的关系将会是"地下情"
or our affair would be "tainted by deception".
当然 灯亮起来的时候
Of course, the minute the lights came up,
我才明白我是个傻瓜
I saw what a fool I'd been.
看看你 我的天使
Look at you, my Botticelli angel.
我只是一个工具
I was a convenience.
这是约翰尼回到卡莉・路易斯身边的一个诡计
A ruse for Johnny to get back in to Carrie Louise.
他的虚荣心不会允许
His vanity wouldn't allow it, you see.
她再和别人结婚
For her to be married again.
他不能忍受被抛弃
He couldn't bear to be left behind.
是不是雷斯塔瑞克先生说服你
Did Mr. Restarick persuade you
在塞罗科尔德夫人的补药里下毒的
to put poison in Mrs. Serrocold's tonic?
我绝对不会加害塞罗科尔德夫人
I would never lay a finger on Mrs. Serrocold.
绝对不会
Never.
马可
Marks...
预备 跑
Set... Go!
听着 我很喜欢卡莉・路易斯
Look, I'm devoted to Carrie Louise.
我怎么会想着用砒霜
Why would I want to "bump her off" for,
来谋杀她呢
and with arsenic, of all things?
要是我的话 我更偏爱箭毒
Personnally, I got a weakness for curare.
一种被低估了的毒药
A much underrated poison.
再加把劲 警官
Give it some, Sargeant!
这样做到底有什么用
What does all of this aid of, anyway?
只是想把事实串起来
Just trying to get my facts in order.
听到第一声枪响的时候你就站着这 对吗
You were standing here when the first shot was fired, correct?
如果你这样认为的话
If you say so.
我想问
The question is,
屋子里停电的时候
the moment the lights went out at the house,
一个人需要多长时间
how much time does a gentleman need?
需要时间干什么
For what, exactly?
进入屋子 杀了可怜的古尔布兰德森先生
To enter the house, sort up on poor Mr Gulbrandsen,
再逃出来
then out again,
准备进入客厅
ready to your great entrance at the drawing room.
看见没 一分零七秒
See? One minute seven seconds.
凶手比大家想象得快多了
Murderer is a lot quicker than people generally imagine.
我的速度都不及警官的一半
I'm not half as quick as your sargeant.
什么 比不上他的肺活量吗
What? In the sate of his lungs?
但这不科学 不是吗
But it's hardly scientific, is it?
你根本都不知道当时我站在哪
I mean, you don't even know where I was standing.
你就只是听我说说
You only got my word for it.
可能你是爱她的
You might be in love with her,
但你宁愿看她死
but you'd rather see her dead
也不愿让她与塞罗科尔德先生
than happily settled
快乐地在一起 不是吗
with Mr Serrocold, right?
你比达希尔・哈米特[侦探小说家]更糟糕
You're worse than Dashiell Hammett.
该去工厂了
Time to make tracks for the facility.
十五分钟后启幕
The curtain goes up in 15 minutes.
你不会真去吧
You're not seriously going ahead?
很明显 这个表演必须继续下去
The show must go on, apparently.
刘易斯 这不会成功
Oh, Lewis, this is hopeless.
别担心 亲爱的
Oh, don't worry, my love.
印第安人承受得起失败
The Cherokee will take it on the chin.
- 艾德加 你觉得怎么样 - 很好看
- There, Edgar, what do you think? - Very smart, sir.
现在 为了"辉煌之作"
Now, for the "pièce de résistance".
吉娜在哪 我整个下午都没见她
Where is Gina? I haven't seen her all afternoon.
她正在房间里准备
She's getting ready in her room.
她一直嘀咕着... 凯瑟琳
She was muttering about... Katherine?
大家听着 还有十五分钟
OK, everyone, 15 minutes.
我记着我说过你不能进这屋里来
I thought I said you're not to come into the house.
老头 你在害怕什么
What are you so affraid of, old man?
这不明摆着吗
I thought it was obvious,
你杀了可怜的克里斯提安
considering you murdered poor old Christian,
勾搭我的秘书
battered my secretary,
现在你又被指控毒害我的妻子
and now you're accused of poisoning my wife.
收回那句话 不是我干的
Take that back! I did no such thing!
我只在再说事实 老伙计
Simple statement of the facts, old man.
好 来吧 来吧 有本事站起来
Right! Come on, then. Come on. On your feet!
来 来 恭候大驾
All right, all right, whenever you're ready!
-父亲 - 刘易斯
- Father! - Lewis!
约翰尼 这你只能怪自己
Johnny, you have only yourself to blame.
那个小伙子扑向了我
The chap flew at me.
你是被椅子绊倒的 大笨鹅
You tripped over a chair, you silly goose.
我真希望那晚 我能注意一下
I just wished I paid a bit more of attention, that evening,
凶杀案那夜
the night of the murder.
人们习惯于把世界当舞台
One gets so used to see the world as a sort of stage.
一直处于不断地幻想之中
One lives in a state of constant illusion.
尽管只是舞台布景 但它足够真实 对吗
It's real enough, though, isn't it, a stage set?
虽然只是创造的 却如此真实
Contrivance it may be, but it's so real.
用锤子 钉子 木材还有油漆
Hammers and nails. Timber and paint.
发明创造
Contrivance.
当然
Of course.
你去哪
Where're you going?
那个吃生蚝中毒的伙计 他醒了吗
Your chappie with the oysters: has he come 'round yet?
没 还昏迷着呢 你问这干嘛
No. Still out for the count. Why do you ask?
没事
Oh, it doesn't matter.
还有...
And uh ...
谢谢你
and thank you.
为什么谢我
What for?
看这些指甲 看看
Would you look at these nails? Just look at them.
答应我 让我在表演后帮你剪掉好吗
Will you promise you'll let let me cut them for you, after the show,
答应我
uh? Promise?
# 哨兵以为她带了个足球... #
The sentries think it's a football that she carries in...
# 当他们摸的时候 #
And when they feel,
# 问道 "阿森纳会赢吗" #
they ask "Is Arsenal going to win?"
# 他们认为那是亚力克・詹姆斯 #
They think it's Alec James,
# 而不是可怜的安娜・波莱娜 #
instead of poor Ana Bolena
# 她的头 缩在 双臂间 #
with her head...tucked... underneath her arm
with her head...tucked... underneath her arm...
# 她走在血塔上 #
She walks on Bloody Tower
# 她的头 缩在 双臂间 #
with her her head...tucked...underneath her arm ...
嗨 斯蒂文
Hey! Stephen!
爸 吉娜在哪 她在哪 到她上场了
Dad! Where's Gina? Where's Gina? She's next.
- 表演不错 - 谢谢
- Knock them dead, hey? - Thanks.
- 你在看吗 - 我不会错过的
- You're watching? - Wouldn't miss it for the world.
# 她的头 缩在 双臂间 #
With her head...tucked... underneath her arm...
# 在午夜 #
At midnight
- 到你了 去吧 - 我忘了
- Your turn. Go! - Oh! I forgot.
我妻子在哪
Where's my squaw?
你准备好就来了
Ready when you are.
你是哪个部落的
What tribe are you, then?
小心骑兵
Watch out for the cavalry!
刘易斯
Lewis!
该死
Bugger!
我从远方来向你们致敬...
I have travelled far and wide to hail you from...
小吉 小吉
G? G!
我 印第安酋长
To know that I... Chief Running Bear,
为我所爱 必须勇往直前
must brave all for the love of my dear.
我的第三个也是最好的妻子 夏日雨
My third and finest squaw, Summer Rain.
她美丽动人的双眸是那样令人愉悦
Her beauties, beauties eyes pleasantly framed.
她来了
She comes,
丘比特的箭穿过我的心
and I am struck of fresh by Cupid's darts.
她萦绕在我的梦里 我的心里 我的...
She haunts my every wishes, my thoughts, my...
吉娜
Gina?
凯瑟琳
Katherine.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
告诉我这只是一个意外
Tell me it was an accident.
看见没
See?
切断了 用刀片 应该是
Severed. With a blade, I should imagine.
还有一线希望
Still, there is one silver lining.
是什么
What's that?
至少这次 警官和我也是目击者之一
At least this time, my sargeant and I are among the witnesses.
是 当然是
Yes. Yes, of course.
塞罗科尔德先生 这两位受害者
Any known contact between the two victims
在被谋杀之前有什么接触吗
prior to the murders, Mr. Serrocold?
约翰尼和克里斯提安吗
Johnny and Christian?
我没注意到有
None of them that I'm aware of.
一些居民说
According to some of the inmates,
雷斯塔瑞克先生确实摆脱过
Sr. Restarick did headed off
惠特斯特布尔・欧尼斯特所谓的跟踪
with Whitstable Ernest, so called.
是吗
Did he ?
同谋者吗
Co-conspirators?
所以 约翰尼有两个内应来帮他向前妻复仇
So, Johnny had two insiders helping him revenge on the ex.
还有那个叫贝耶维的女人
The convict and the Bellever woman.
这还只是我们知道的几个
And that's just the ones we know about.
过来 边界这里需要更多地人
Come on, I want more men on these borders!
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
简 怎么了
What is it, Jane?
- 你没有站起来喝茶 - 没
- You're not standing for your tea. - No.
今天不行
Not today.
可怜的约翰尼
Poor Johnny.
我的错爱
My favorite mistake.
你可以跟我说说凯瑟琳的事吗
Would you tell me about Katherine?
- 谁 - 凯瑟琳・埃尔斯沃思
- Who? - Katherine Ellsworth.
女杀人犯
The murderess.
1927年9月4日在波特兰被绞死
Hanged, 4th of September 1927, in Portland.
"埃尔斯沃思夫人在三宗砒霜投毒案中
"Mrs. Ellsworth, found guilty on
被认定为有罪
three counts of poisoning with arsenic
穿着一件简单的印花棉裙子走上绞刑架
wore a simple dress of printed cotton on her final journey to the gallows.
她只在拒绝接受祷告时开口说了几句..."
She spoke only to decline the offer of prayers..."
你在哪找到的
Where did you find that?
今早 在吉娜的房间里
In Gina's room, this morning.
凯瑟琳・埃尔斯沃思是吉娜的生母 对吧
Katherine Ellsworth was Gina's birthmother, wasn't she?
是
Yes.
可以从她女儿身上看到同样的冲动
And the same urges can be seen in the daughter.
我告诉过她 吉娜就是神秘的投毒者
I told her, Gina is our mystery poisoner
还有 昨晚她弄的那个
and... last night's ridiculous
金黄色发型真是滑稽
carry on with that blond hairdo,
使她和那个女凶手看起来很像
making herself look like that murderess,
让我妈妈心烦
to upset mummy
简直就是... 一个公开的忏悔
was nothing less than... a public confession.
我承认现在还不清楚
I admit I'm at a loss to know
吉娜是怎么知道这一切的 但...
how Gina came to learn of all this, but uh ...
可能是有人故意把这张报纸
perhaps someone put the newspaper there
放在那边让她看见的
for her to discover.
不可能
That's impossible.
没人知道 就连刘易斯也不知道
No-one knew. Not even Lewis.
只有我自己和米尔德里德
Only myself and Mildred.
米尔德里德
Mildred?
你怎么能这样 她是你姐姐
How could you? She's your sister!
你总是说 我们应该分享
You always said...we should share.
但她不肯
Well, she won't.
她不与我分享
She won't share.
从未有过
She never did.
不仅是你
Not you.
她夺走了所有人
Not anybody.
我可怜的吉娜
Oh, my...my poor darling Gina.
你觉得她在责怪我吗
Do you think she blames me?
你觉得昨天晚上她故意穿成那样
D'you think last night she was trying to hurt me
是对我这么多年一直对她隐瞒的报复吗
for keeping it from her all these years?
也可能为了伤害自己
Or hurt herself.
我一定要去找她 跟她谈
I must go to her, speak to her.
卡莉・路易斯 也许你应该两边都谈谈
Carrie Louise, perhaps you should speak to them both.
也许这样你才能平息这多年的阴影
Together, perhaps you could lay this particular ghost to rest.
我还是先喝完茶吧
I think I'll finish my tea first.
我想若世界上没有那么多秘密
I think we would all sleep a lot better in our beds
也许我们晚上就能安然入眠
if there weren't quite so many secrets in the world.
你了解多少了
How much do you know?
我并不确定
If I was quite sure...
我知道你已经清楚了
Oh, I think you're sure.
你想要我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
做你唯一能做的 去跟探长先生说
The only thing you can do. Talk to the inspector.
等我喝完这杯茶
Just as soon as I finish my tea.
是约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克让我想到的这点
It was Johnny Restarick that gave me the idea.
把这间屋子不看作一间会客厅
To think of this room, not just a drawing room ...
可以的话把窗帘向左拉一些
Oh, a little to the left, if you wouldn't mind.
就这样
Just so. Um ...
不是简单的一间会客厅
Not just a drawing room,
而是一个摆满道具的场景
but as a stage set.
就是这样
There.
一个戏剧晚会
An evening of dramatics.
向平常一样的出入口
The usual entrances and exits.
当然 还有后场 也就是外面的平台
And backstage, of course, outside, on the terrace.
包括我在内的观众坐在这
The audience, myself included, sat here,
被一个把戏所吸引
audient by a conjuring trick.
他们利用了"魔镜"
They do it with mirrors.
- "魔镜" - 这不是行话吗
- Mirrors? - Oh, isn't that the common slang?
一些很简单的误导行为
A few, simple acts of misdirection.
首先是停电
First, the power cut.
你认为停电是有人故意为之的
You think the lights were meant to go out.
我相当确定
Oh, I'm quite sure of it.
你记得白天的那次断电吧
You recall the power cut early in the day,
就是他们晚饭前用灯来试验的那次
set off by the spotlights that were being tested before supper.
那时候保险丝就被设置好
The fuse box was then primed to blow a second time
以待在会客厅的线路过载时再次跳断
when the circuit of the drawing room was overloaded.
- 断电了 - 线路跳断了
- Oh, block. - Wires on the blink.
我去看看保险丝
I'll go and check the fuse box.
是那个美国人吗 瓦利・哈德
The north-american? Wally Hudd?
这将我引向了第二个误导
Oh. Which brings me to the second misdirection.
能不能...
Oh. Would you mind?
- 暗门 - 对
- The hidden door. - Yes.
我们判断这边是凶手的第二个出口
Now, here we deduce, was the killers second exit.
当然停电的时候 没人知道发生了什么
And, with the lights out, of course, nobody can be sure of anything,
使得你有了更多的嫌疑人 探长先生
leaving you, Inspector, with a far wider cast of suspects.
如果这暗门与谋杀根本无关呢
What if the the door had nothing to do with the murder?
如果凶手用更加简单的方法出去了呢
Hm? What if the killer made a far simpler escape?
永远不要低估那些显而易见的事实 探长先生
Never underestimate the power of the obvious, Inspector.
确实 那么...
Indeed. So ...
请坐
Would you ...
现在
Now,
那两个人从落地窗走到平台上
two men step through the french windows onto the terrace.
但我们事实上看到的是什么
But what do we see? What do we actually see?
当然 有艾德加・罗森
Edgar Lawson, of course,
但塞罗科尔德先生去哪里了
but what became of Mr. Serrocold?
我们听见了他的声音
We heard him.
- 谢谢 塞罗科尔德先生 - 艾德加
- Thank you, Mr Serrocold. - Edgar!
- 不许动 - 够了
- Nobody move! - That's enough.
另一个把戏
Another trick.
艾德加是在模仿...
Edgar was simply mimicking the voice of ...
- 刘易斯・塞罗科尔德的声音 - 对
- Lewis Serrocold! - Mm-hm.
凶手根本不需要花任何时间
The killer would have taken no time at all.
比你手下一分零七秒更快
No more than your sargeant's one minute and seven seconds.
动机呢 我从没见过那么爱自己妻子的男人
But why? I never saw a man so devoted to his wife.
确实如此
Quite.
但我们怎么知道是否真的有个投毒者
But how do we know there really was a poisoner?
看看现有的证据
Look at the evidence.
卡莉・路易斯的关节炎仅仅是个巧合
Carrie Louise's arthritis was a coincidence, nothing more.
她用的药
And her tonic,
在十一点时被混入了极少量的砒霜
mixed at eleventh hour with very few drops of arsenic,
不是为了杀死卡莉・路易斯
intended not for Carrie Louise,
而是想让你和你的同事去发现
but for you and your colleagues to discover.
另外当塞罗科尔德先生在检查尸体时
A few words were then added to the letter
他在信中加了一些字
when Mr. Serrocold examined his body.
我有理由相信
I have reason to believe
她正慢慢地被人下药毒害
she is being slowly and cold-bloodedly poisoned.
我最初有此怀疑是在...
I first suspected it when...
这样信的意思就变了许多
And the meaning was quite altered.
所以并没有人想要毒害塞罗科尔德夫人
So, there never was any plot to poison Mrs. Serrocold.
是的 探长先生
No, Inspector.
我知道约翰尼也如此怀疑
And I'm sure Johnny suspected as much.
因为很奇怪地
Hence his rather odd desire
他在死前一直想要剪卡莉・路易斯的指甲
to trim Carrie Louise's fingernails a few minutes before he died.
剪下的指甲样本能很快证明
A sample of nail-clipping would soon have proven
她的血液中并无毒素
there was no arsenic in her bloostream.
- 但他如何知道... - 就在花园里
- But how could he possibly... - There, in the garden,
在去房子的路上
on his way up to the house,
他看了一眼那后台
he had a glimpse of the backstage, as it were.
尽管起了雾 但有枪声和脚印
Even through the fog. Gunshots. And footsteps.
当他如此友好地对待欧尼斯特时
And when Johnny befriended Ernest at the facility,
我认为他那时就开始就一片一片地
I'm sure he began to piece together
拼凑起这个毒害骗局背后的情况
the hidding story behind the poisoning hoax.
在欧尼斯特房间里的那些东西
as for all those treats in Ernest's room
威士忌 钥匙 生蚝
the single malt whiskey, the keys, the oysters ...
不是偷来的
.. They weren't stolen.
而是刘易斯・塞罗科尔德送他的
They were gifts from Lewis Serrocold.
是一个利用自己高超的诈骗挪用技巧
Grateful tokens to a man whose rare talent for fraud and
来挽回信用基金损失财产的人得到的奖赏
embezzlement had helped restore the fallen fortune of Gulbrandsen Trust
但为什么
But why?
那样一个正直的绅士
An upstanding gentleman like that.
"一切都为了爱"
"The things we do for love."
是不是这样
Wasn't it like that,
塞罗科尔德先生
the way you put it, Mr Serrocold?
不错
Quite right.
简
Jane.
克里斯提安・古尔布兰德森
Christian Gulbrandsen
发现了你的经济问题
had discovered your slide into
并打算揭发此事
financial corruption and sought to expose it.
但因为他对卡莉・路易斯的感情
Only his affection for Carrie Louise
使他停下了脚步
gave him pause.
他问我"她的心脏是否强壮"
Was her heart strong, you see.
你肯定知道
You must have known,
就在七周前
he was onto you,
他把受托人都召集到斯托尼盖特的时候
the last time Christian came to Stonygates.
你就知道他是冲你来的
When the Trustees convened, seven weeks ago,
那时你就开始构思你的计划了 对吗
that's when you conceived your plan, wasn't it?
先是那场火
First, the fire,
不是电路故障起火
started not by faulty wiring,
而是你的同谋
but by your accomplice,
惠特斯特布尔・欧尼斯特纵的火
Whitstable Ernest.
他藏在暗门
Concealed behind the hidden door.
只是留下了一些汽油滴下的痕迹
Only he left a few tale trail drops of petroleum.
因此我们会在那里闻到柴油的味道
The smell we talked of diesel on the floor boards.
那场火真正的目的
The real target of those flames
并不是你妻子的照片或是遗嘱
wasn't your wife's photographs or even her will,
而是档案柜里的账目记录
it was the accounts records housed in the filing cabinet.
这为你争取了不少时间
That bought you some time,
但你知道 克里斯提安不会这样放过你
but you knew Christian couldn't be put off forever.
你就打算在他下次来斯托尼盖特时杀他灭口
And so you were ready to silence him when he next came up to Stonygates
这个改造工厂花光了我们所有积蓄
The reform facility ate up all we had.
那些地产 还有那些无休止的特权
The buildings. The endless privileges.
我只有这样...
It was the only way ...
我已经把所有东西都砸了进去
I poured everything in it.
信托基金
The Trust.
我自己的财产
My own fortune.
这是最后一搏了
It was the last resort.
你也明白 不是吗
You see that, don't you?
这是我能唯一想到的 让你开心点的方法了
It was the only way I knew to make you happy.
你若发现...
If you found out...
你不必向我证明你如何爱我
You didn't have to prove yourself to me.
但约翰尼・雷斯塔瑞克正虎视眈眈
With Johnny Restarick waiting in the wings?
- 约翰尼 - 我看到了他的信
- Johnny? - I saw his letters to you.
- 那个人十分疯狂 - 不
- The man was unstoppable. - No!
你才是我的丈夫
You are my husband.
你知道一些 不是吗
You knew a little, didn't you?
我在想 当约翰尼...
I wondered. When Johnny...
他还没有套到什么话
His new friendship had to be scotched,
他和惠特斯特布尔・欧尼斯特的朋友关系
before Whitstable Ernest
就结束了
let something slip.
生蚝里混入的砒霜使他坏不了事
The arsenic in the oysters kept Ernest out of the harm's way.
那约翰尼呢
And Johnny?
我想是一次算好时间的谋杀
A spontaneous killing, I would wager,
当他在后台的照明设备下面时
while he was under that lightening operators ...
有人听那男主角的一句台词便下手
.. waiting for a word with the leading man.
但你一直在舞台上
But you were on stage all the time.
如果不是你...
If it wasn't you ...
艾德加・罗森
Edgar Lawson!
父亲
Father?
- 艾德加 - 警官快去
- Edgar! - Sargeant!
- 艾德加 - 孩子
- Edgar! - Son!
艾德加
Edgar!
快点 快
Come on! quick!
伙计们 赶紧
Hurry up, lads!
快
Quick!
继续找
Keep looking!
- 你知道艾德加的事情吗 - 我在想
- Did you know? - I wondered.
刘易斯总是很快就结束了
Lewis was always quick to end
任何有关于艾德加身世的讨论
any idle talk about Edgar's true provenance.
再看看艾德加自己
And then there was Edgar himself.
他的疯癫... 看起来不太让人信服
His madness... seemed unconvincing somehow,
似乎在寻找一个失踪的父亲 我很遗憾
the quest for a missing father. I. .. I'm so sorry.
刘易斯 为什么他不直接告诉我呢
Oh, Lewis. Why didn't he just tell me?
可能他怕你不会接受
Perhaps too scared you wouldn't approve.
就以我自己这样的经历吗
What, with my check at history?
至少他自己为了救他的孩子而死
Well, at least he died trying to save his own son.
也许能给人带来一点安慰
I try to take some comfort in that.
也许这意味着他终究是个善良的人
And maybe that means he was a good man, after all?
好像英勇地战死一般
Like being bulleted, back in the war.
- 小心点 - 不能那么弄
- Be careful with that. - I wouldn't do that if I were you.
这是一个暗门 来 我给你看
It's part of a hidden door. Here, let me show you.
- 亲爱的 帮我一下 - 当然
- Oh, help me, darling. - Of course.
真是聪明
So clever.
简 走吧 我们已经够迟的了
Come on, Jane. We're late enough already.
飞机四点起飞
The flight leaves at four,
飞行员可不会等我们
and, apparently, the pilot refuses to wait.
当然
Of course.
你确定不改主意了吗
Are you sure you won't change your mind?
这个时候的曼哈顿真的很棒
Manhattan is fabulous at this time of the year.
谢谢你 鲁思 我确定
Quite sure, thank you, Ruth.
英国的破电路
Damn british wiring.
马上来
One minute.
该死
Damn!
瓦利
Wally!
你去哪了
Where've you been?
你在这做什么
What're you doing here?
你错了
You're wrong.
我查了一下
I looked it up.
这是红木 不是巨杉树
They're red-wood, not Wellingtonia.
这刺太硬
The bur's too tough.
看见没
See?
- 看见没 - 瓦利 别这样
- See? - Wally! Don't!
停下
Stop!
瓦利
Wally.
现在你让我伤心了
Now you've got me started.
- 瓦利 我... - 别说了
- Wally, I... - No.
都安排好了
It's all settled.
那就重新安排
Then unsettle it.
笑什么 你为什么总是这样
What? Why do you always do that?
对不起
I'm sorry.
在我想说些什么的时候开始笑
Laughing when I'm trying to say something.
我...
I...
我不敢相信你还喜欢我
I just can't believe you still want me.
你还没明白吗
Don't you get it?
我从来没有...
There was never...
从来没有哪一刻我不...
not a single moment that I...
不怎样
When you what?
过来
Come here.
蜜儿 亲爱的
Mil! Sweetie!
- 你来的正好 - 是吗
- You look just the ticket! - Do I?
不想来试试吗
Fancy a spin?
不用了 谢谢
Thank you, but no. I don't think so.
再也不会了
Not anymore.
蜜儿 蜜儿
Mil! Mil!
亲爱的简阿姨
My dear aunt Jane,
我希望你知道我们怀俄明州这边
I wanted you to know that we seem to be prospering,
快要丰收了
after a fashion, here in Wyoming.
我还是打算成为一个美国女孩
I decided to be an american girl, after all.
他们说在那里 你来自何方不重要
They say that here, it's not where you come from that accounts,
重要的是你如何面对你的人生
it's what you make, with the life you were given.
在过去经历了那么多以后
After all this past, after all that's gone before,
我梦想得到的这些是否太过奢侈呢
Is it too much to dream that such a thing is possible?
爱你的 吉娜
All our love, Gina